A Guide to the Frederick Swartwout Cozzens Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7509
Frederick Swartwout Cozzens Collection 1851-1868
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7509
ca. 18 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Deposit, [1963 Dec 17], 1964 May 11
Item Listing
- Manuscript
  - "To My Big Sweetheart", [1860]; AMsS
    [Poem]
- Letters
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to George William Curtis, 1851 Jan 2; ALS, 1 p.
    [Thanks him for book (
    Hadad
    by James A. Hillhouse).]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to George William Curtis[Rocky Mountain Howadji], 1851 Oct 25; ALS, 1 p.
    [Invitation to visit Cozzens at Chestnut Cottage after lecturing; mentions the Century Club, J. F. Kensett, and to Stopson.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to Henry [Pointer], 1853 Jul 29; ALS, 1 p.
    [Not able to give him "the Verplanck sketch" on short notice.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to George William Curtis[Howadji], 1854 Nov 18; ALS, 1 p.
    [Concerns lecture dates for Curtis in Yonkers. ]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to George William Curtis, 1854 Nov 29; ALS, 1 p.
    [Mentions illness, enjoyment of Curtis' lecture, and "auspicious beginning for our young library."]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to George William Curtis[Howadji], 1855 Nov 6; ALS, 1 p.
    [Refers to availability of certain cigars from Cozzens' import business.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to Mr. Seaver, 1856 Aug 6; ALS, 1 p.
    [Unable to find several people Seaver asked about; requests printing bill for Seaver's billheads.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to W. C. Westervelt, 1857 Sep 1; ALS, 2 p.
    [Mentions his St. Lawrence trip; will supple Westervelt with back numbers of some publications; mentions Southern wines have too much sugar.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to Childs and Peterson, 1858 Apr 19; ALS, 2 p.
    [Re additions to Cozzens biography published by them.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to [ George William Curtis], 1861 Jul 27; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks for picture; mentions sending own picture to Curtis.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to George McLaughlin, 1863 Dec 11; ALS, 3 p.
    [Refers to request for manuscript of
    Sparrowgrass Papers
    . ]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to Fitz-Greene Halleck, 1863 [Jan 24]; ALS, 4 p.
    [Favorable comments on poem sent by Halleck; refers to William Cullen Bryant, Wordsworth, Thackeray, Century Club, George Bancroft, G. C. Verplanck; is working on some notes and anecdotes regarding Washington Irving. ]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to son, 1865 Sep 13; ALS, 1 p.
    [Discusses Professor Drowne's advice that son repeats a year; suggests son keep Drowne's letter; compliments him on hunting.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to Ford B. McGuire, 1868 Jun 1; ALS, 1 p.
    [Refers to financial trasactions and attempt to sell country house.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to George William Curtis, n.d.; ANS, 1 p.
    [Accepts invitation.]
  - Frederick Swartwout Cozzens to George William Curtis[Howadji], n.d.; ALS, 1 p.
    [Cover note for books sent to Curtis, one borrowed from Pierre Van Courtlandt. ]
- Prints
  - 3 Prints of Frederick Swartwout Cozzens by Charles Loring Elliot and J. C. Buttre, Prints